<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Release | Vợ Ba Con]]></title>
  <link href="http://v3k.net/blog/categories/release/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://v3k.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-09T22:12:23+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://v3k.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Truong]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[v3knet@toila.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drupal 7.25]]></title>
    <link href="http://v3k.net/blog/2014/01/09/drupal-7-dot-25/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T21:45:34+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://v3k.net/blog/2014/01/09/drupal-7-dot-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://drupal.org/drupal-7.25-release-notes">Release notes</a> còn nhiều mục khác
nữa, tôi không thấy hứng thú gì với mấy cái đó nên khỏi note.</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>Added an optional feature to the Statistics module to allow node views to be
tracked by Ajax requests rather than during the server-side generation of the
page. This allows the node counter to work on sites that use external page
caches (string change and new administrative option: <a href="https://drupal.org/node/2164069">https://drupal.org/node/2164069</a>).</p></blockquote>

<p>Tính năng rất thú vị cho các website chịu tải cao nhưng vẫn sử dụng module
statistic #performance #statistics</p>

<blockquote><p>Added a meta tag to install.php to prevent it from being indexed by search
engines even when Drupal is installed in a subfolder (minor markup change).</p></blockquote>

<p>Nhớ có lần tôi truy cập vào domain nọ, bản Drupal của họ chỉ để đó, chưa có
install gì hết. Tôi cài giùm họ, cấu hình với SQlite database, kết quả là Drupal
chạy vèo vèo. Lúc đó, tui mà táy máy, bật module PHP lên, rồi chạy các script độc
độc thì không biết sẽ lụm được gì trên con server đó nữa… Tới nay thì lỗi này đã
được fix rồi. Hôm nay đọc thấy cái fix này, tôi thấy cũng hay hay #install #seo</p>

<blockquote><p>Performance improvement: Prevented block rehashing from writing blocks to the
database on every cache clear and cron run when the blocks have not changed.
This fix results in an extra &lsquo;saved&rsquo; key which is added and set to TRUE for
each block returned by _block_rehash() that actually is saved to the database
(data structure change).</p></blockquote>

<p>Bắt bệnh hay #performance #hash</p>

<blockquote><p>Added an optional &lsquo;skip on cron&rsquo; parameter to hook_cron_queue_info() to allow
queues to avoid being automatically processed on cron runs (API addition).</p></blockquote>

<p>Chừ thì tôi mới biết có hook này tồn tại ((= #hook #cron #api</p>

<blockquote><p>Made the File and Image modules more robust when saving entities that have
deleted files attached. The code in file_field_presave() will now remove the
record of the deleted file from the entity before saving (minor data structure
change).</p></blockquote>

<p>DB sạch hơn chút với patch này.</p>

<blockquote><p>Fixed broken tests on PHP 5.5.</p></blockquote>

<p>Có vẻ như Drupal 7 chạy rất ổn định trên PHP 5.5? Có thể, nhưng tôi chỉ e ngại
các module mở rộng! #php55 #stable #qa</p>

<blockquote><p>Changed the database API to allow inserts based on a SELECT * query to work
correctly.</p></blockquote>

<p>Tính năng hay nhưng rất ít khi tôi sử dụng, <code>INSERT INTO … SELECT …</code>, người ta
dùng nhiều và có bug, và bug đã fix #sql #db</p>

<blockquote><p>Changed the database schema of the {file_managed} table to allow Drupal to
manage files larger than 4 GB.</p></blockquote>

<p>Ghê! Dùng Drupal lưu trữ file 4GB luôn #db #schema</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
